<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xavier Martinez</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xavier Martinez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I am currently a post-doctoral fellow at LBT (Laboratoire de Biochimie Theorique) in Paris, in Marc Baaden&amp;rsquo;s team working on UnityMol, a molecular viewer built in Unity game engine.
During my Ph.D at LIMSI, VENISE team in Orsay under supervision of Patrick Bourdot, I worked on creating a tangible interface for interacting with molecular simulations like protein-protein docking or IMD (interactive molecular dynamics). Thanks to a recent collaboration between Nicolas Férey and Bastien Vincke, the project evolved to embed electronical parts like sensors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Vincke, B., Ghaoui, M.A., Férey, N., Martinez, X., 2020. Physical, Modular and Articulated Molecular Interface for Interactive Simulation. Sensors. DOI: 10.3390/s20185415
  Martinez, X., Hardiagon, A., Santuz, H., Murail, S., Barboiu, M. Sterpone, F., Baaden, M., 2020. Using Computer Simulations and Virtual Reality to Understand, Design and Optimize Artificial Water Channels. Advances in Bionanomaterials, Springer, Cham. DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-47705-9_8
  Martinez, X., Baaden, B., 2020. FAIR sharing of molecular visualization experiences: from pictures in the cloud to collaborative virtual reality exploration in immersive 3D environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase</title>
      <link>/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/showcase/</guid>
      <description>        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
